Gagan Malvi

Platform and Systems Engineer

malvigagan@gmail.com +91 944-91-16454 https://malvi.tech Vellore, Tamil Nadu

A capable developer working on Android platform and Linux internals. Works with various chipsets and their BSPs, with over 4 years of collective experience. Familiar with system administration and site reliability, and a recognized developer at XDA-Developers.

Languages

English - Fluent Hindi - Intermediate

Education

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

VIT, *Vellore* 2020 - 2024

Current CGPA: 8.36

XII (Senior Secondary), CBSE

Sri Chaitanya, Bengaluru 2020

Percentage: 91.4%

X (Secondary), CBSE

Kendriya Vidyalaya NAL, Bengaluru 2018 Percentage: 91.0%

Experience

Paranoid Android - Systems Engineer

Jul 2020 - present

- Brought up and maintained various Android devices on AOSPA/CodeLinaro/CodeAurora codebases, worked on device bring-up, improving performance and overall user experience on these platforms.

Luganodes - Site Reliability Engineer Intern

June 2023 - August 2023

- Worked on setting up the nodes and working on monitoring for several blockchain nodes namely SSV, Ethereum on Goerli, The Graph, and Substrate.
- Used tools like **Grafana**, **Prometheus**, **Loki**, **Mimir**, **Docker**, **Podman** and **Compose**.

FloMobility - Platform Engineer

Jan 2023 - May 2023

- Helped set up and coordinate the development of the operating system platform based on **AOSP** for **FloEdge**, an outdoor grade powerful edge computer that is ready to deploy for any robotics and AI applications.

Teracube Inc - Platform Engineer

Feb, 2021 - Mar 2023

- Spearheading **Teracube Open Devices** getting all our devices to work on AOSP with **open source trees**. Working on platforms **MT6765** and **MT6771**.
- Working on the **Android 12 platform update** for the Teracube One; feature parity, and performance improvements.
- Working on MediaTek BSPs (10, 11, 12) to provide software updates for Teracube smartphones, and working on aftermarket operating systems for the same, including certification testing (CTS/VTS/etc) for GMS.

Projects

The Styx Project

https://github.com/StyxProject

August 2020

- A lightweight AOSP-based aftermarket distribution aiming to provide speed, stability, enhanced battery, reduced bloat and the subtly-enhanced beauty of stock Android to users.
- Features many improvements to AOSP to improve performance, and overall user experience.
- Supported by over 30 devices across 5 OEMs.
- Many improvements over AOSP to improve privacy and security.
- Supported Android versions: Android 11, 12.

Cobra

https://github.com/gaganmalvi/cobra-cli

February 2023

March 2021

- A proof-of-concept intrusion prevention system making use of KVM, libvirt, and QEMU.
- Calculates performance metrics and determines if the system is under attack, and blocks the attack accordingly.
- Part of a university course project.

Arcadia Linux

https://github.com/arcadialinux

- A Linux-based distro aiming for speed, performance and a great overall experience on portable devices and workstations.
- Based on Arch Linux, purely made to learn about Linux internals and to create a distro that would be perfect for the end user.

Other projects

https://github.com/gaganmalvi

Certifications

LFD103: A Beginner's Guide to Linux Kernel Development (The Linux Foundation) Issued Sep 2021

Show credential